Daniel J. Hanson, MAI

Dan Hanson graduated from the University of Oregon in 1988, and has been a real estate appraiser and consultant in the Portland metro area and southwest Washington since 1992. In 2008, he formed Hanson Valuation LLC, and joined Appraisal & Consulting Group in 2013. Mr. Hanson has specialized expertise in the appraisal of office and retail properties, and also has substantial experience appraising vacant



land residential subdivisions, proposed townhome/rowhome development, industrial, and special use properties. Special-use properties appraised include hotel/motel properties, gas stations, churches, RV parks, mobile home parks, self-storage and RV storage facilities, among others.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science - Finance, Accounting Minor, University of Oregon, 1988

APPRAISAL INSTITUTE COURSES

Course I400, 7-Hour National USPAP Update, 2012

Course N420DM, Business Practices and Ethics, 2011

Course 410, Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice, 2007

Course 550, Advanced Applications, 2006

Course 540, Report writing & Valuation Analysis, 2004

Course 510, Advanced Income Capitalization, 2003

Course 530, Advanced Sales Comparison and Cost Approaches, 1995

Course 520, Highest and Best Use and Market Analysis, 1994

Course 1B-A, Capitalization Theory and Techniques: Part A, 1992

Course 1B-B, Capitalization Theory and Techniques: Part B, 1992

Course 1A-1, Basic Valuation Procedures, 1992

Course 1A-2, Real Estate Appraisal Principles, 1992

OTHER APPRAISAL COURSES AND SEMINARS

Appraisal Curriculum Overview

Comparative Analysis

AI/ABA Telebriefing – New Interagency Appraisal & Evaluation Guidelines (1/2011)

What Commercial Clients Would Like Appraisers to Know

Appraising Distressed Commercial Real Estate

An Introduction to Valuing Green Buildings

Attacking & Defending an Appraisal in Litigation

Analyzing Operating Expenses

Appraising from Blueprints & Specifications

Subdivision Analysis

EXPERIENCE

Owner, Hanson Valuation LLC, 2008 to 2013

Commercial Appraiser, Cassinelli Jackson LLC, 1999 to 2008

Commercial Appraiser, Palmer, Groth & Pietka, Inc., 1992 to 1998

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

MAI, Appraisal Institute

STATE CERTIFICATIONS

Oregon, State Certified General Appraiser, License No. C000657

Washington, Certified General Real Estate Appraiser, Certificate No. 1100786